Guide to the Philip Rose Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Papers, 1969-2006; Series IV; 0.5; (1 box)
  - Other Material
    - Various clippings - memoirs, circa 2001 (Box 20 Oversize, Folder 279)
    - Reproduction photograph of Philip Rose, mounted (Box 20 Oversize, Folder 280)
- Audiovisual Material, 1970s-1998; Series V; 3.5; (4 boxes)
  Material is arranged in rough chronological order.
  This series contains audio and visual recordings chiefly documenting the production Shenandoah, but also includes recordings of Purlie and You Shouldn't Have Told.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 13-16 (audiovisual material): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Sing a Christmas Song, audiocassettes, circa 1970s-1980s
    Contains various audio recordings on compact cassettes, including four published copies of Purlie: Original Broadway Cast, one published copy of Shenandoah: Original Broadway Cast Recording, and nine home produced tapes labelled "Sing A Christmas Song: A Light Rap Opera". The commercial audiocassettes have not been digitized.
    - Sing a Christmas Song, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613915)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Sing a Christmas Song by Peter Udell and Garry Sherman, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613923)
    - Sing a Christmas Song by Peter Udell and Gary Sherman, abridged, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613931)
    - Sing a Christmas Song by Peter Udell and Garry Sherman, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613949)
    - Sing a Christmas Song by Peter Udell and Garry Sherman, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613956)
    - Sing a Christmas Song demo, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613964)
    - Sing a Christmas Song demo, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613972)
    - Sing a Christmas Song, a light rap opera (demo), undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613980)
    - Sing a Christmas Song by Peter Udell and Garry Sherman, abridged, undated; 1 (Box 13, Item barcode 39002104613998)
  - Shenandoah, audiotape reels, 1975 September 18
    Contains five large monophonic audio reels, recorded at CBS Records.
    - #111924, Reel 7, 1975 September 18; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002104613725)
      A list of contents is included with this audiotape reel.
      Freedom and Freedom Encore
      Violets and Silver Bells
      RR Sequence
      Papa
      Only Home
      Only Home Reprise
      Papa Reprise
      Meditation II
      Meditation Seque
      Pass the Cross
      Pass the Cross Finale
      Freedome Finale
    - #111924, Reel 3, 1975 September 18; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002104613733)
      Raise the Flag, Part 1
      Raise the Flag, Part 2
      I've Heard It All Before
      Pass the Cross (Cross-over)
      Why Am I Me
      Next to Lovin
      Over the Hill
      The Pickers are Coming
    - #111924, Reel 2, 1975 September 18; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002104613741)
      Beautiful Pair
      It's a Boy (+ insert)
      Freedom (+ repeat from banjo)
      Violets and Silver Bells (reprise)
      Freedom Finale
    - #111924, Reel 5, 1975 September 18; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002104613758)
      Next to Lovin' (reprise)
      Meditation I
      Bedroom Segue
      Violets and Silver Bells, Part 1
      Violets and Silver Bells, Part 2
      It's a Boy
      It's a Boy (insert for end)
      Finale, Act 1
      Act 2, Opening
    - #111924, Reel 1, 1975 September 18; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002104613766)
      Raise the Flag
      Next to Lovin'
  - "Blaine Thompson 'Shenandoah' SH-3MED 'Meditation' Generic: 60 Cullum. Reeves Teletape Studios", circa 1975; 1 (Box 15, Folder 287)
    Contains a single two-inch video teletape from Reeves Teletape, New York. Box is labelled: Blaine-Thompson - "Shenandoah" - SH-3MED - "Meditation Generic" - [John] Cullum.
  - Shenandoah, Meditation, Papa-Baby, Meditation (U-Matic videocassette), circa 1975; YCALMSS438_0002; 1; 00:04:01 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002102301836)
    Contains two Betamax videocassettes.
  - Shenandoah, audiotape reels, 1975-1978
    - Music Master A, 1978 January 27; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614426)
    - Music Beds, 1975 April 22; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614434)
      Contents include: "Papa's Gonna Make It", "Freedom", "Next to Lovin'", "Why Was I Born", "Stand and Show Your Colors", "The Dream Has Turned" and "This Farm".
    - Third copy of corrected Shenandoah bells, 1977 November 25; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614442)
    - Show SFX, flutter or pitch deficiency on church bells; distortion on train bell, new tape, 1976 November 22; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614459)
    - Side II, 1975 February 11; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614467)
    - Shenandoah Music Master B, 1978 January 27; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104618344)
    - Shenandoah Job # 111924, undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104618351)
      A list of contents is included.
      1. Beautiful Pair
      2. Violets + Silverbells (wedding)
      3. It's a Boy
      4. Papa
      5. Freedom
      6. V + S Reprise
      Second Meditation
    - Side Two, revised, 1975 February 19; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614475)
    - Shenandoah, undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614483)
    - copy, side one, revision, 1975 February 18; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002104614491)
      Why Am I Me?
      First Meditation
    - Show Tape, 1977 December 8; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613774)
    - Side Ic, undated; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613782)
    - IIc, undated; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613790)
      Next to Loving
      Freedom
    - Side I, 1975 February 11; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613808)
    - Side I, original, undated; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613816)
      There is a list of contents included with this audiotape reel.
    - Side II, 1975 February 11; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613824)
    - Side I, 1975 February 11; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613832)
    - Music Tracks for TV, vocals, 1975 April 9; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613840)
      This is a list of contents included with this audiotape reel.
      Papa - Opening
      Papa - Closing
      Papa - Closing, edited with intro and without [delay]
    - Background for commercial, band only, undated; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613857)
      Contents include: "It's a Boy" and "Freedom".
    - Music tracks for TV with vocals, 1975 April 11; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613865)
      "Freedom" (no music bridge)
      "Papa" (from the top, two-bar intro)
      "Next to Lovin'" (two-phase intro, ends "most")
      "First Meditation" (This land here...")
      "Second Meditation" (The dream...")
      "I've Heard It All Before"
      "Why Am I Me" (two choruses, no intro)
    - Music :30 TV, 1977 April 21; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613873)
      Contents include intro, dance, and vocals.
    - Radio, piano, undated; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613881)
      Contents include: "Freedom" and "Meditation".
    - WoWoWoWoWo, 1977 April 27; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613899)
      Contents include two :30 TV
    - With Vocals, 1975 May 5; 1 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002104613907)
      "Next to Lovin'"
      "Freedom"
      "Meditation"
      "Papa"
  - Shenandoah (videocassette, U-Matic), undated; YCALMSS438_0003; 1; 00:09:56 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002102301844)
  - You Shouldn't Have Told, WABC News Channel 7 (videocassette), 1998 August 4; YCALMSS438_0004; 1; 00:07:08 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002102301851)
    Contains two VHS cassette recordings from WABC News, Channel 7, New York.
  - You Shouldn't Have Told, WABC News Channel 7 (videocassette), 1998 August 4; YCALMSS438_0005; 1; 00:04:06 (Box 16, Item barcode 39002102301869)